<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<metadata
        xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
        xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
        xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
    <dc:title>Analysis of Correlation Between GDP per Capita and Average Height of Young Adults in 2019 in 164
        Countries
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>Lea Salome Brugger</dc:creator>
    <dc:subject>Correlation Between GDP per Capita and Average Height of Young Adults</dc:subject>
    <dc:description>Experiment which investigates the correlation between the GDP per capita and average height of
        female and male 19-year-olds in 2019 in 164 countries.
    </dc:description>
    <dcterms:abstract>The aim of this experiment is to find out whether there is a (strong) correlation between the
        gross domestic product (GDP) per capita of a country and the average height of its 19-year-old inhabitants. For
        this purpose, data from two publicly available datasets were used: One dataset concerns the GDP per capita and
        the other contains data about the mean height of girls and boys of different ages per country. Both datasets
        consist of data collected over the course of several years; the year of interest for this experiment is 2019.
        The data entries from the two datasets were matched by comparing the country name given in the respective entry.
        Only countries are taken into consideration for which both datasets yield complete information - in total, 164
        countries were considered in the experiment.
    </dcterms:abstract>
    <dc:date>19.04.2021</dc:date>
    <dc:type xsi:type="dcterms:DCMIType">Dataset</dc:type>
    <dc:format xsi:type="dcterms:IMT">text/csv</dc:format>
    <dc:source>The World Bank: GDP per capita (current US$) (2021)</dc:source>
    <dc:source>NCD Risk Factor Collaboration: Height - Evolution of adult height over time (2021)</dc:source>
    <dc:language xsi:type="dcterms:ISO639-3">EN</dc:language>
    <dcterms:temporal xsi:type="dcterms:Period">2019-2019</dcterms:temporal>
    <dcterms:license xsi:type="dcterms:URI">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dcterms:license>

</metadata>